Guide to the Time Inc. Life Editorial Records 1937-2013 MS 3009-RG 9
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV.A. Senior Editor Gene Farmer Files, 1958-1972, 2005-2006; 10 Linear feet in 10 record cartons
  - Subseries IV.A.2. First on the Moon: A Voyage with Neil Armstrong, Michael Collins and Edwin E. Aldrin, Jr. Files, 1963-1971, 2005; 230644; 9 Linear feet in 9 record cartons
    - Subsubseries IV.A.2.c. Research, 1963-1971; 230670; 7 Linear feet in 7 record cartons
      - Space Shuttle [RESTRICTED], 1969?; 233114 (Offsite-box 2227)
        1 audiotape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 5 in., 1/4 in. tape. Label on container: "Time Inc. - Space Shuttle Audio - tk. 1. AVL-Pulse-tk. 3."
      - Time Inc. Reception Center Press Conference [RESTRICTED], 1969; 233115 (Offsite-box 2227)
        1 audiotape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. Label on container front: "Spot checked this tape on 7/8/03. It seems to be only the introduction to the press conference (by Jerome Hardy?). The rest of the tape appers to be blank. BH." Label on container back: "J Hardy 7/11/69. Reception Center. Astronauts Press Conference. July 11/69."
      - Unidentified Audiovisual [RESTRICTED], undated; 233112 (Offsite-box 2227)
        1 audiocassette (Norelco C-90): analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. All labels crossed out.
- Series IV.B. Senior Editor Jonathan Larsen Correspondence, 1981; 231775; 0.1 Linear feet in 2 record cartons
  Jonathan Larsen's correspondence is primarily letters to the editor and story proposals.
  Materials remain in original order.
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Offsite-box 2214, Folder 30-31)
- Series V. Staff Writer Dora Jane Hamblin Research Interviews for That Was the Life [RESTRICTED], 1975; 230283; 0.5 Linear feet in 1 record carton
  Dora Jane "Dodie" Hamblin's recorded interviews with Life staff for her book That Was the Life published in 1977. Unreformatted audiovisual material in the collection is not accessible.
  Organized alphabetically by last name of interviewee on the container label.
  - Angus, Ann, 233032 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette (Certron): analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On paper wrapping tape: 'French - Cassette. Ann Angus. Does not fit American Tape Player. For D. Hamblin's Book. Life. 1975.' Label on Side 1: 'Ann Angus Denny Lonlon.' Label on Side 2: 'Ann Angus Denney Lonlon.'
    1 audiocassette (Certron): analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. On paper wrapping tape: Ann Angus - French Cassette. Cannot play on American tape. For D. Hamblin Book 1975.' Label on Side 1: RA Carthage.' Label on Side 2: Ann Denny Angus and husband Archie.'
  - Bacon, Dorothy, 233033 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette (Certron): analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'BACON, DOROTHY Hamblin interview (French Cassette - cannot play).' Label on Side 1: Dorothy Bacon, London: Churchill - (___ era).' Label on Side 2: 'D. Bacon and at end DJH recalling other interviews.'
  - Graves, Eleanor and Ralph; and Richard Pollard, 233034 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'GRAVES, E & R., POLLARD, RICHARD 1975 LIFE (D. Hamblin book interview).' Label on Side A: 'Dick Pollard Graves.' Label on Side B: 'GRAVES Ralph & Eleanor.'
  - Hall, Muriel, 233035 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'HALL, MURIEL (Hamblin book interview). Kennedy Assanation. Vietnam. Notre Dame. LIFE.' Label on Side 1: 'MURIEL HALL - Kennedy.' Label on Side B: 'MURIEL HALL - Vietnam & Notre Dame.'
  - Hamblin, Dora Jane; and several others, 233037 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette (Toshiba microcassette): analog; 1 15/16 x 1 5/16 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'HAMBLIN, DORA JANE REMINISCENCES-LIFE 6/86.' Label on Side A: 'Hamblin, Dora J. 6/86 Life.' On paper wrapping tape: 'HAMBLIN, DODIE 6/86? self interview for book, 'That Was Life'.'
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'HAMBLIN, DORA J. (BOOK RSCH. WITH Sargent, Peggy; Wellemeyer, Marilyn; Scholl, Jane; Morse, Ralph.)' Label on Side A: 'Hamblin, D. '75. Wellemeyer & Scholl.' Label on Side B: 'Marilyn & Jane, Bea & all.' On paper inside container: 'tape begins Peggy Sargent and her husband Paul. Barbara mentioned is Barbara Brewster. The Mary is Mary Leatherbee. We then switch to Marilyn Wellemeyer, Jane Scholl, Mary Jane Grunsfeld (not a staffer) and me, DJH. Most of it is Wellemeyer and Scholl. Side 2 is Wellemeyer and Scholl, about midway Betty Dunn comes in. Also Bea Dobie. Then at the end Ralph Morse talking about photography.'
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'HAMBLIN, DODIE with McQuiston, NicolaiC. FennellH. LIFE stories for Hamblin book.' Label on Side 1: 'J. McQuiston & Clara Nicolai, then Fennell.' Label on Side 2: 'Helen Fennell then McQuiston.'
  - Hunt, George; and others, 233038 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'HUNT, GEORGE (D. Hamblin interview) II Picasso issue; Russian issue.' Label on Side 1: 'begins Joanne McQuiston-next Helen Fennell.' Label on Side 2: 'George Hunt.'
  - MacPhail, Marian, 233039 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'MAC PHAIL, MARIAN (Dodie Hamblin interview). LIFE - Head of Research - reminiscences.' Label on Side 1: 'MacPhail.' Label on Side 2: 'Marian MacPhail.'
  - Mason, Janet, 233040 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'MASON, JANET (Dodie Hamblin interview). LIFE reminiscences.' Label on Side 1: 'Side 1: Janet Mason, LIFE no date. Prob. 1975.' Label on Side 2: 'Jan Mason LIFE II.'
  - McQuiston, Joanne, 233041 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'McQuiston, Joanne (Hamblin Book Interview). LIFE - NY, Paris, London, 'Epic of Man' Egypt.' Label on Side 1: 'McQuiston, Joanne. Hamblin book.' Label on Side 2: 'McQuiston.'
  - Moffatt, Hugh, 233042 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'MOFFETT, HUGH - reminiscences TAPE I. Life - for Dodie Hamblin's 'That Was the Life.' 1975.' Label on Side A: 'Hugh Moffett I'. Label on Side B: 'Moffett TR.'
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'MOFFETT, HUGH - reminiscences TAPE II. Life - for Dodie Hamblin's 'That Was the Life.' 1975.' Label on Side A: 'Hugh Moffett - Side 1. II'. Label on Side B: 'Hugh Moffett, 2.'
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'MOFFETT, HUGH - reminiscences TAPE III. Life - for Dodie Hamblin's 'That Was the Life.'' Label on Side A: 'Hugh Moffett IIIA'. Label on Side B: 'Hugh Moffett IIIB'.
  - Morse, Ralph, 233043 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'MORSE, RALPH (D. Hamblin Book Research) Life Photographer - Astronauts etc.' Label on Side A: 'Ralph Morse - on photographing NASA.' Label on Side B: 'BLANK.'
  - Nicolai, Clara, 233044 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'NICOLAI, CLARA (D. HAMBLIN interview). LIFE reporter - reminiscences: side 1 - Mafia story; side 2 Andria Doria story.' Label on Side 1: 'Clara Nicolai. Mafia.' Label on Side 2: 'Nicolai. Cattle in studio. Andrea Doria.'
  - Osborne, Charles; and Valerie Vondermuhll, 233045 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'OSBOURNE, CHARLES (D. Hamblin Book Rsch). Vondermuhll " 1975.' Label on Side 1: 'Charles Osborne & Val Vondermuhll.' Label on Side 2: 'C. Osborne & Vondermuhll.'
  - Prideaux, Thomas, 233046 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'PRIDEAUX, THOMAS (D. Hamblin interview for book, THAT WAS THE LIFE 1975.' Label on Side 1: 'Tom Prideaux.' Label on Side 2: 'Prideaux Prideaux LIFE.'
  - Sargent, Peggy; and Ralph Graves, 233047 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'SARGENT, PEGGY (D. Hamblin Interview) (Short interview with Graves, E. & R).' Label on Side 1: 'Side 1: Ralph Graves & Peggy Sargent.' Label on Side 2: 'Side 2. Sargent.'
  - Stolley, Richard, 233048 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'Stolley, Richard (D. Hamblin Research) (first 15 min of side 1 of tape is of a group of women researchers).' Label on Side A: 'Dick Stolley 2.' Label on Side B: ' "Women" Stolley 1.'
  - Thompson, Edward; and Marian MacPhail, 233049 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'THOMPSON, E.K. #1 A&B D. HAMBLIN interview for book. 1975?' Label on Side 1: 'Edward K. Thompson I-A.' Label on Side B: 'THOMPSON, E.K. by D. Hamblin. 1975 #1A & B.'
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'THOMPSON, E.K. #2 A&B. D. HAMBLIN interview for book. 1975?' Label on Side 1: 'THOMPSON, E.K. by D. Hamblin. 1975 #2 A&B.' Label on Side B: 'EKT.'
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'THOMPSON, E.K. #3 A (MARIAN MAC PHAIL - SIDE B). D. HAMBLIN interview for book.' Label on Side 1: 'THOMPSON, E.K. by D. Hamblin. 1975 #3A (Marian MacPhail - Side B.' Label on Side B: 'Side 2 Marian MacPhail.'
  - Vondermuhll, Valerie, 233051 (Offsite-box 2215)
    1 audiocassette: analog, 1 5/16 ips, stereo; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Label on container: 'VONDERMUHLL, VALERIE - (D.Hamblin book "That Was the Life" 1975.' Label on Side 1: 'Side I: Valerie Vondermuhll. Aug.-Sept. 1975.' Label on Side 2: 'LIFE.'
- Series VI. Photographer Alfred Eisenstaedt Files, 1946-1995; 191147; 5 Linear feet in 3 record cartons and 2 flat boxes
  Alfred Eisenstaedt was born in Dirschau, West Prussia (present day Tczew, Poland) in 1898 and became interested in photography in his early teens. His interest in photography was interrupted for a time when he was drafted into the German army as an artilleryman. He was injured during his service and sent home for rehabilitation.
  After the war, Eisenstaedt moved to Berlin to work as a salesman and used his free time to study and experiment with photography. In 1927, his photograph of a girl playing tennis was bought by Der Welt Spiegel, an illustrated weekly, and published as a back-of-the-book feature.
  Eisenstaedt kept photography became a full-time photographer in 1929. His first position was as a special photo reporter for Pacific and Atlantic Photos. In 1931, Pacific and Atlantic Photos was taken over by the Associated Press, and Eisenstaedt remained emploted with the Associated Press.
  In 1935, Eisenstaedt moved to the United States and took a position with Life by 1936. Eisenstaedt was one of four photographers to work in the original photography department and was a staff photographer for publication of the first issue. After joining Life, Eisenstaedt became known for his photographs of political leaders and movie stars. In addition to these subjects, Eisenstaedt also photographed America rebuilding after the depression, Japan during the war and post-war era, and the people and rulers of nations throughout the continent of Africa. His best known photograph may be of the Time Square kiss on V-Day.
  Along with having his photographs featured in Life, Eisenstaedt has also published a number of books including Witness to Our Time, The Eye of Eisenstaedt, Martha's Vineyard, Witness to Nature, Wimbledon: A Celebration, People, Eisenstaedt's Guide to Photography, Eisenstaedt's Album, and Eisenstaedt: Germany.
  Before his death in 1995, Eisenstaedt had completed twenty-five thousand assignments for Life and had received numerous awards for his work. Among the awards he received were Photographer of the Year from the Britannica Book of the Year and the University of Missouri School of Journalism in 1951, the Clifton C. Edom Award for Photographic Achievement from Kappa Alpa Mu Nation Photojournalism Fraternity in 1953, the Culture Prize in Photography from the Germany Society of Photographers in 1962, the International Understanding Award for Outstanding Achievement in Photography in 1967, the National Press Photographers Association Joseph A. Sprague Memorial Award in 1971, and the Lifetime Achievement Award in Photography from the American Society of Magazine Photographers in 1979. Along with his awards, Eisenstaedt was voted as one of the world's greatest photographers in a 1968 poll conducted by Popular Photography and was present with the #1,000,001 Leica Camera by E. Leitz Inc. in 1961.
  Alfred Eisenstaedt's files cover the period of 1931 to 1995 and focus on his time as a photojournalist at Life. The files include general material that looks like it was cleared from his desk, scrapbooks, and drafts for his book Witness to Our Time.
  Subseries VI.A: Desk Papers
  Subseries VI.B: Scrapbooks and Ephemera
  Subseries VI.C: Witness to Our Time
  - Subseries VI.A: Desk Papers, 1946-1995; 191183; 3 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
    The Desk Papers contain materials that look like they were collected from Alfred Eisenstaedt's desk at Life. Records include correspondence from fans and industry professionals; news clippings; drafts of press releases; copies of photographs; negatives; lists of photograph captions; price lists; transcripts of interviews; essays and profiles on Eisenstaedt; press kits; exhibition materials for exhibits including his work; event brochures; trip itineraries; assignment reports; handwritten notes; maps; and various awards.
    - The Artist of Merit Josef Sudek Medal, 1989; 191225 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 1)
    - Awards and Tributes, 1967-1992; 191224 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 2)
    - BBC Interview, 1984; 191223 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 3)
      Includes audiovisual material.
      1 audiotape reel: 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On label: "Title: Eisenstaedt. No.: SNAP Reel" 6-15-84".
    - Biographical Details, 1967-1995; 191222 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 4-5)
    - Book Draft, undated; 191220 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 6)
    - Book Proposal, undated; 191219 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 7)
    - Brazil with Alfred Eisenstaedt, 1973; 191218 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 8)
    - City of New York: Mayor's Award of Honor for Arts and Culture, 1988; 191217 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: General, 1961-1973; 191216 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Birthday and Holiday Cards, 1993; 191215 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Complaints about Sofia Loren Cover, 1966; 191214 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Fan Letters, 1975-1995; 191213 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Photographic Copies, circa 1960-circa 1990; 191212 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 14-17)
    - Correspondence: Professional, 1967-1993; 191211 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 18)
    - Endorsement? Clip, 1979; 191210 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 19)
      1 film reel (30 sec.); 7.5 mm. On container: "6/29/79, Chiat/Day, Fotomat, QFBD 1043, -Eisenstaedt Rev.1-, Color, 3 sec."
    - Events and Exhibits, 1955-1993; 191209 (Offsite-box 2216, Folder 20-25)
    - Events and Exhibits, 1955-1993; 191203 (Offsite-box 2217, Folder 1-5)
    - Famous Artists School, 1961; 191202 (Offsite-box 2217, Folder 6)
    - FYI Memorial Issue on Henry Luce, 1967; 191201 (Offsite-box 2217, Folder 7)
    - International Center of Photography: Twelfth Year Report, 1986; 191200 (Offsite-box 2217, Folder 8)
    - The International Who's Who: 1991-92, 191199 (Offsite-box 2217, Folder 9)
    - Interviews, 1986; 191198 (Offsite-box 2217, Folder 10)
    - Life: Gift Subscription (Nuit de Noel), 1962; 191197 (Offsite-box 2217, Folder 11)
    - London Dispatches, 1951-1952; 191196 (Offsite-box 2217, Folder 12)
    - Magazine Articles About and Mentions, 1956-1992; 191195 (Offsite-box 2217, Folder 13-14)
    - Maps, undated; 191194 (Offsite-box 2217, Folder 15)
    - News Clippings and Releases, 1966-1992; 191193 (Offsite-box 2217, Folder 16-20)
    - News Clippings and Releases, 1966-1992 (Offsite-box 2218, Folder 1)
    - Photo Essay Assignments: Captions and Reports, 1946-1970; 191192 (Offsite-box 2218, Folder 2-4)
    - Photo Essay: Draft, undated; 191191 (Offsite-box 2218, Folder 5)
    - Photo Essay Assignments: Shooting Plans and Schedules: Papers, 1958, undated; 191190 (Offsite-box 2218, Folder 6)
    - Photo Essay Assignments: Shooting Plans and Schedules: Film, 1968?
      Includes three cannisters of negatives associated with the Great Lakes photo shoot.
      The cannisters are respectively labeled: "Life: Pollution: Part I: The Great Lakes: History and Ecology," "Life: Pollution: Part II: The Great Lakes: Causes of Pollution," and "Life: Pollution" Part III: the Great Lakes: Results of Pollution."
    - Photograph Print Orders, undated; 191189 (Offsite-box 2218, Folder 7)
    - Photographs and Captions, 1993, undated; 191188 (Offsite-box 2218, Folder 8-9)
    - Press Releases, 1967-1987; 191186 (Offsite-box 2218, Folder 10)
    - Time-Life International: Special Project: World War II, 1966; 191184 (Offsite-box 2218, Folder 11)
    - General, 1966, undated (Offsite-box 2218, Folder 12-13)
  - Subseries VI.B: Scrapbooks and Ephemera, 1983-1993; 191176; 0.5 Linear feet in 6 oversize folders
    The Scrapbooks and Ephemera series contains items presented to Alfred Eisenstaedt by Time Inc. and other institutions.
    - Alfred Eisenstaedt: 25 Years of Photography, undated; 191182 (Offsite-box 2278, Folder 1)
      Contains a bound book of photographs of the exhibit.
    - Alfred Eisenstaedt Day: Chicago Proclamation, 1991; 191177 (Offsite-box 2278, Folder 2)
    - Alfred Eisenstaedt Day: New Jersey Proclamation, 1993; 191180 (Offsite-box 2220, Folder 5)
    - Lecture: Southwest Craft Center Chapel, undated; 191181 (Offsite-box 2220, Folder 6)
    - Life Masthead Photographer Designation, undated; 191179 (Offsite-box 2220, Folder 7)
    - Miami University Honorary Doctorate Scrapbook, 1983; 191178 (Offsite-box 2278, Folder 3)
  - Subseries VI.C: Witness to Our Time, 1947-1966; 191148; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton and 1 oversize folder
    The majority of materials in this series are drafts of chapters written for the book and lists of captions for the photographs in the book. Also included are handwritten notes, news clippings, and a limited amount of correspondence.
    Organized by book chapter with full drafts at the end.
    - Papers (Offsite-box 2218, Folder 14-35)
    - Papers (Offsite-box 2219, Folder 1-8)
    - Oversized (Offsite-box 2220, Folder 8)
- Series VII. Letters Department Reports, 1937-1972; 0.5 Linear feet 1 microfilm box including 8 reels of microfilm
  Letters Department reports include summaries of reader letters and lists of known errors. All reports in this series on available on microfilm only. All dates refer to the contents, not date of imaging. Some original reports from 1969 to 1971 are in Managing Editor Ralph Graves Files.
  Organized by Life publication then chronologically based on the original order.
  - Life Letters, 1937 November-1943 May (Box 2348, Reel 1)
  - Life Letters, 1943 August-1952 October (Box 2348, Reel 2)
  - Life Letters, 1957 November-1958 April (Box 2348, Reel 3)
  - Life Letters, 1958 May-1962 November (Box 2348, Reel 4)
  - Life Letters, 1962 December-1966 August (Box 2348, Reel 5)
  - Life Letters, 1966 September-1972 June (Box 2348, Reel 6)
  - Life Letters, 1972 July-December (Box 2348, Reel 7)
  - Life International Letters, 1946-1970 (Box 2348, Reel 7)
  - Life en Español Letters, 1953-1959 (Box 2348, Reel 7)
  - Life en Español Letters, 1960-1969 (Box 2348, Reel 8)
- Series VIII. Consent Releases [RESTRICTED], 1952-1972; 231776; 5 Linear feet in 5 record cartons
  Organized alphabetically by magazine section or department with general at the front and unidentified at the end.
  Editorial Consent Releases are releases signed by interviewed or photographed subjects of articles collected by the magazine department or section responsible for the article. Some releases are organized by article title. Departments and sections include Art, Closeups, Crime, Domestic News, Education and Religion, Education and Youth, Entertainment, Fashion, Foreign News, Images, Manners and Morals, Miscellany, Modern Living, Nature, Newsfronts, Parties, Photography, Religion, Science, Speaking of Pictures (SOP), Sports, Special Projects, Text, and Text and Reports.
  - General-Education and Youth (Offsite-box 2221)
  - Education and Youth-Manners and Morals (Offsite-box 2222)
  - Manners and Morals-Science (Offsite-box 2223)
  - Science-Special Projects (Offsite-box 2224)
  - Special Projects-Unidentified (Offsite-box 2225)
- Series IX. John Loengard Interview Project Videotapes [RESTRICTED], 1992-2005; 231851; 4 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
  Historical Note
  John Loengard was a Life staff photographer from 1961 to 1971 and Picture Editor from 1978 to 1987. From 1992 to 1994, he conducted videotaped interviews with former Life staff photographers including himself, and used these interviews to write his 1998 book Life Photographers: What They Saw.
  Bill Hooper, email message to Deakyne, March 23, 2017.
  Ronk, Liz. "The Beatles, Marilyn Monroe and More: Photographs by John Loengard." Time, December 6, 2016. http://time.com/4588308/moment-by-moment-john-loengard/.
  This series includes videotapes of Loengard's interviews with Life staff photographers. Unreformatted audiovisual material in the collection is not accessible. Transcripts from these interviews were filed into the respective Bio Files in RG 2 by the Time Inc. Archives, but not all interviews may have a transcript.
  Organized alphabetically by last name with transfer forms at the front.
  - Archives Transfer Forms, 2005; 232025 (Offsite-box 2197, Folder 1)
  - Benson, Harry, 231885 (Offsite-box 2197, Item 1-4)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Benson Interview (1/10/92)."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Benson Interview (1/10/92)."
  - Birns, Jack, 231884 (Offsite-box 2197, Item 5-6)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Birns Interview 8/14/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Birns Interview 8/14/93."
  - Bristol, Horace, 231883 (Offsite-box 2197, Item 7-8)
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Bristol Interview 8/13/93."
    1 videocassette (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Bristol Interview 8/13/93."
  - Capa, Robert, 231882 (Offsite-box 2197, Item 9-12)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "Master Copy. The Research Center, Time Inc. Capa Interview 10/25/93."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Capa Interview 10/25/93."
  - Clark, Ed, 231881 (Offsite-box 2197, Item 13-16)
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "ED CLARK. interview with John Loengard. November 3, 1993. Copy from Time Inc. Archives."
    2 videocassettes (VHS). On label: "The Research Center, Time Inc. Clark Interview 11/3/93."